Finding Aid for Michigan Association of Teacher Educators records, 1947-1983
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Association of Teacher Educators records 1947-1983
Michigan Association of Teacher Educators.
3 linear feet
85281 Bh 2
Organization of educators responsible for directing or supervising the work of student teachers. Annual reports, conference files, minutes, newsletters, and other records of the organization.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the president and executive secretary of the Michigan Association of Teacher Educators (donor no. 6948 ) in July 1983.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
On May 3, 1947, representatives from six state teacher-training institutions met at what was then Michigan State College. Participants at the meeting agreed to form an organization of educators in schools, colleges, and universities who were responsible for directing or supervising the work of student teachers. This organization became the Michigan Association for Student Teaching, a state unit of a national association. In September 1970 the national organization became the Association of Teacher Educators. The state unit adopted a new constitution in February 1972, and became the Michigan Association of Teacher Educators.
The records of the Michigan Association of Teacher Educators have been arranged alphabetically, then chronologically. These records, 1947-1974, include minutes, correspondence, conference programs, newsletters, materials relating to the election of officers, and membership lists.
Subjects:
Education--Michigan.; Teachers--Michigan.
- Organizational records
  (arranged alphabetically by type of records)
  - Annual Report of the Executive Secretary
    - 1967-1973, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Committees
    - Professional Standards 1966 (Box 1)
    - Standards and Performance 1972-1974 (Box 1)
    - Teacher Education and Professional Standards 1952 (Box 1)
  - Conferences
    - March 1966 (Box 1)
    - June 1968 (Box 1)
    - November 1968 (Box 1)
    - February-March 1969 (Box 1)
    - April-May 1969, May 1969 (Box 1)
    - November 1969 (Box 1)
    - February 1970 (Box 1)
    - May 1970 (Box 1)
    - November 1970 (Box 1)
    - February 1971 (Box 1)
    - April-May 1971 (Box 1)
    - November 1971 (Box 1)
    - April 1972 (Box 1)
    - April 1973 (Box 1)
    - November 1973 (Box 1)
    - May 1974 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1966-1974 (Box 1)
  - Constitution
    - 1948 (Box 1)
    - 1959 (Box 1)
    - 1964 1967 (Box 1)
    - 1968 (Box 1)
    - 1971 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - 1952-1953 (Box 1)
    - 1969 (Box 1)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - MEA 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Elections
    - 1966 (Box 1)
    - 1968 (Box 1)
    - 1969 (Box 1)
    - 1970 (Box 1)
    - 1971 (Box 1)
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
    - 1974 (Box 1)
  - Executive Board
    - 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1967-1973 (Box 1)
  - Executive Secretary
    - 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Executive Secretary's Notebook 1971-1974 (Box 1)
  - General Information
    - 1964-1967 (Box 2)
    - 1968 (Box 2)
    - 1969 (Box 2)
    - 1970 (Box 2)
    - 1972 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Guidelines for Professional Excellence (Box 2)
  - MEA Teacher Education Task Force (Box 2)
  - Meetings
    - 1963 (Box 2)
    - 1965 (Box 2)
    - 1966 (Box 2)
  - Membership
    - Brochures (Box 2)
    - Lists
      - 1947-1953 (Box 2)
      - Undated 1966-1967 (Box 2)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 2)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Minutes
    - 1947-1952 (Box 2)
    - 1952-1955 (Box 2)
    - 1955-1959 (Box 2)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 2)
    - 1962-1970 (Box 2)
    - 1964-1967 (Box 2)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Newsletters
    - 1947-1952 (Box 3)
    - 1953-1958 (Box 3)
    - 1959-1964 (Box 3)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 3)
    - 1969 (Box 3)
    - 1970-1974 1983 (Box 3)
    - Association for Student Teaching 1967-1970 (Box 3)
    - Association of Teacher Educators 1970-1974 (Box 3)
  - Publications of national organization (Box 3)
  - Task Force on the Future of MAST 1971 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer's Reports 1966-1973 (Box 3)